Michael Hammond

<u>Michael.Hammond714@gmail.com</u> | 519-505-6285 <u>LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mike-j-hammond/</u>

Portfolio: https://gamnrd.github.io/# | Github: github.com/gamnrd

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Enthusiastic and skilled game developer eager to apply my college education and lifelong self-taught expertise to contribute to a career in game development. Dedicated and detail-oriented individual with over 10 years of experience in programming and developing games, possessing excellent communication and prioritization skills, quick learning and very determined.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Proficient in Unreal Engine and Unity for developing PC, mobile, and VR games.
- Skilled in Windows application development using C, C++, and C# within Visual Studio.
- Experience in creating web applications using HTML, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Proficient in developing macros using VBA and VBScript in Microsoft Excel.
- Analytical and result-oriented with strong mathematical aptitude.
- Excellent people skills, fostering effective communication and relationships.
- Hardworking and dedicated individual with high work ethics.
- Ability to remain professional and composed in challenging situations, adapting promptly to changes.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Technology

Conestoga College Waterloo ON 3.66 GPA

2020 - 2023

Completed the Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering Technology from Conestoga College with a focus on Game Development in the final year. Key coursework included Game Design, Game Development, and AR/VR Development.

- Developed Windows, Web, Android & VR applications.
- Proficient in C, C++, C#, HTML, CSS, JS, Java & Python.
- Utilized Unity, Unreal Engine, Visual Studio / VS Code, GIT, Blender, and Android Studio.
- Emphasis on Object-oriented Programming, data structures, and algorithms.
- Applied industry best practices for robust computing systems.
- Project management principles and tools for efficient requirements implementation.
- Proficient in Computer Architecture and Machine Language.
- Strong background in Math and statistics for Software Development.
- Experience with Computer Architecture, Boolean devices, truth tables and logic operations.
- Practiced Agile and Scrum methodologies in team projects.

Continuous learning: Expanding on learning new languages and skills through sources such as Udemy, W3 Schools, Zenva and other online tutorials. See the education tab in the portfolio for a list of recent online courses completed.

Electronic Arts - Virtual Experience Program on Forage - July 2023

Developed a new feature idea with a proposal, designed a class diagram, created a header file to define the feature classes, and optimized and debugged a sample project.

Projects

All project downloads and code bases can be found here: https://gamnrd.github.io/#projects

The Final WaveZ – mobile zombie top down shooter (In Development)

Created in Unity as a final project for the Simulation and Game Development class, this project has evolved into a wave-based shooter with an economy and upgrade system. Since graduation, I've been actively revamping and expanding the game, increasing performance, utilizing object pooling, a custom events system, AI state machine and more. The goal is to transform it into a comprehensive mobile game for eventual publication.

• Technologies Used: Unity, C#, Github, Windows, Android

VR Hospital Evacuation Simulation - VR training simulation

As part of the Augmented/Virtual Reality course, I participated in the creation of a VR fire evacuation simulation. The client, Cambridge Memorial Hospital, commissioned us to develop a proof-of-concept VR simulation for fire evacuation scenarios.

• Technologies Used: Unity, VR, C#, Github, Meta Quest 2

Stealth Game – 3rd person stealth game

This project, conceived during the Game Development course, focused on building a stealth game with AI integration. The player's objective is to navigate through levels while evading patrolling guards. To enhance gameplay, I implemented a noise system to simulate the guards' ability to detect sound cues such as running and object interactions.

• Technologies Used: Unity, C#, Github, Windows

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Department Manager – Loblaws

2018-2022

- 10+ years of training new staff on all aspect needed to become a cashier and/or supervisor.
- Managing the schedules of 50+ cashiers and supervisors.
- Oversee store and account closing.
- Maintain cash handling procedures.
- Completed regular workplace safety training, such as WHIMS.
- SMART SERVE certified.
- Experienced with Starbucks, within a Loblaw's environment.

Front-End Supervisor - Loblaws

2014-2018

- Excellent supervisory skills, managing medium to large employee groups.
- Excellent problem-solving skills with customers.
- Working in a unionized environment.
- Perform corrective actions, overrides, cash control, refunds.

•

Cashier 2008-2014